mysensors.org 2017-06-06

# Privacy Policy | MySensors - Create your own Connected Home Experience

## Privacy Policy

 _Last updated: January 1, 2016_

This privacy policy covers Sensnologys collection and treatment of information and data collected when you visit Sensnology Websites or use Sensnology Services.

  1. DEFINITIONS
    1. “Sensnology” means the entity Sensnology Corporation.
    2. “MySensors.org” and "OpenHardware.io" is the name of the product and service provided by the Sensnology Corporation.
    3. “Services” means the any and all services and hosted software applications provided by Sensnology, including but not limited to, OpenHardware.io, MySensors API, the MySensors Cloud, MySensors Forum, MySensors website or any other software services offered by Sensnology.
    4. “You” means yourself and any entities you represent.
    5. “Products” means the physical products sold by Sensnology.
    6. “Third Party Products” – includes but is not limited to applications, websites, APIs, software, or hardware that interacts with, uses or connects to any Sensnology Products or Services.
    7. “Website(s)” means any web domains owned, operated, branded or co-branded by Sensnology. Websites include community forum.
  2. HOW SENSNOLOGY COLLECTS DATA
    1. Information You provide
      1. When You create an account on OpenHardware.io, You provide us with data that includes an email address and password. Sensnology may also give you the option to voluntarily share other data with us that is connected to your account. If any of these details change, You may update your account at any time and modify, correct or delete your account details.
      2. You may choose to contribute to, and interact with, the Sensnology Websites including the MySensors Forum Website. You will have the opportunity to control which information, in addition to Your required user name, that you would like to share to other forum members and mySensors users. You may choose whether to display or provide your contact details and other personally identifiable information on the Websites.
      3. Our Sites and/or Services may allow you to share information with others. Please note that if you choose to share information about yourself in an open format, such as through Third Party Sites and/or Services, or in any user-generated content elements of our Websites and/or Services, we consider that information to be public information – and not personal information. Remember that when you share information publicly, it may be indexed and accessed by search engines.
      4. When You actively provide information on Sensnology Websites, for example when You post a message or interact with the MySensors Website, Sensnology may retain that data about You for later use. This data is stored on secure third party servers.
    2. Sensnology collects certain data from visitors to the Sensnology Websites in order to continuously improve and enhance our customers' experience. This data is collected via the following methods:
      1. The OpenHardware/MySensors Website and forum, like many other websites, will store session information (often called “Cookies”) in your browser that will help Sensnology to analyze usage information such as browsing activity, IP addresses and page view order. You do have the option to not use these Cookies; the majority of browsers will have a “help” tool that will help you to prevent Cookies if you want to, but Sensnology recommends you keep Cookies active as it will provide a better user experience on the Sensnology Websites.
      2. When You visit the Sensnology Websites, the MySensors web servers automatically log typical website analytic data from visitors to our Website. This data, that may include details such as browser type, IP addresses, site visit length and referral URL, is used for systems administration, detecting usage patterns and generally improving the customer experience.
      3. OpenHardware.io collects non-personally identifiable data when You use the Sensnology Services. OpenHardware.io associates this data with the account details You supplied when you created your account and stores it securely on Third-Party servers.
    3. Information provided by third parties
      1. At times Sensnology may collect information from Third-Parties that use our Services or Products. They may provide us with Personal or Anonymous Data that we will use to continue to improve our Services and Products.
  3. HOW IS DATA KEPT SECURE?
    1. We use Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption for the APIs (Application Programming Interface) and Websites operated by Sensnology.
    2. Data collected by Sensnology via its Websites and Services is stored on secure third-party servers.
  4. HOW IS DATA USED BY SENSNOLOGY?
    1. The data referenced in this Privacy Policy is primarily used by Sensnology to improve, troubleshoot and enhance Products, Websites and Services.
    2. Email addresses and any other information supplied by You may also be used by Sensnology to respond to emails, phone calls and requests. In addition Sensnology may use identification data such as controller id to associate it with Your account and to provide information and technical assistance to You. For example, Your email address and device details may be used to respond to a technical support question that You send to Sensnology.
    3. Sensnology may collect and create anonymous data by excluding personally identifiable information. Sensnology reserves the right to use Anonymous Data for any purpose and disclose Anonymous Data to third parties at its sole discretion.
  5. WHEN IS DATA SHARED?
    1. Sensnology may at some point authorize a third-party to process or analyze some of the data we have collected.
    2. Sensnology may share aggregated or anonymous data publicly.
    3. When appropriate, Sensnology may share data with entities and persons who are actively doing business with Sensnology and have entered into a contract with Sensnology Organization. A company of this sort will have access to the data generated by individuals who are users of the product created and sold by said company.
    4. Sensnology will share personal information with companies, organizations or individuals outside of Sensnology if we have a good-faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of the information is reasonably necessary to:
      1. Meet any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request.
      2. Protect against harm to the rights, property or safety of Sensnology, our users or the public as required or permitted by law.
      3. Enforce applicable Terms of Service, including investigation of potential violations.
      4. Detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues.
    5. If another company acquires Sensnology or our assets via a merger or acquisition, that company will possess the Personal Data collected by Sensnology and will assume the rights and obligations regarding your Personal Data as described in this Privacy Policy. In this event Sensnology will notify You via email or by publishing a message on the website before any data is transferred.
  6. ADDITIONAL STUFF
    1. Our Sites and/or Services may allow you to share information with others. Please note that if you choose to share information about yourself in an open format, such as through Third Party Sites and/or Services, or in any user-generated content elements of our Sites and/or Services, we consider that information to be public information – and not personal information. Remember that when you share information publicly, it may be indexed and accessed by search engines.
    2. Third-Parties may occasionally offer products or services that interact with Sensnology services. Sensnology will encourage these Third-Parties to follow a similar privacy policy as this one, but you acknowledge and agree that Sensnology is not responsible for the privacy policies of others.
    3. Sensnology reserves the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy at any point without prior notification and approval. Continued use of the Websites and Services once these changes are announced will confirm Your approval of, and agreement to, any and all changes.
    4. Sensnology will not intentionally gather information from children under the age of 13.
    5. If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy you may contact Sensnology at [info@sensnology.com](mailto:info@info@sensnology.com).
